KARAN SHARMA

RZ-20, Bajaj Enclave, Old Palam Road, Dwarka Sec-15, New Delhi-78 +91-9555597928

karanarman52@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/karan-sharma-7500ba171/

Profile

Experienced and self-motivated Human Resource Professional with 4 years & 5 months of industry experience including Talent Acquisition, Induction & Onboarding, and Operations, Administering policies & procedures and Payroll processing in the Human Resource Department of the rapidly growing organizations. Adapt in implementing programs & Changes that enhance company positions and lead to success. Knowledge about employment laws & effective organization planning. Bringing forth a proven track record of successfully managing Human Resource efforts & serving as a crucial pillar of support of HR teams & employees.

Educational Qualification

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Masters of Business Administration in Human Resource, and Finance with 70%

Dwarka, New Delhi Graduated, June 2019

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Bachelors of Business Administration (General) with 68%

Dwarka, New Delhi, *Graduated, June 2016*

Sarvodya Bal Vidayalaya

Higher Secondary Education with Commerce with 67 %

Kakrola, New Delhi Graduated, May 2013

Spring Meadows Public School

Secondary Education with 6.8 CGPA

Dwarka More, New Delhi Graduated, May 2011

Internship & Project

SHAREKHAN LTD.

Financial Advisor (8 weeks)

New Delhi, Delhi

- Understanding the importance of "Investment in Share Market & Mutual Funds".
- Identifying Investment's needs & building Positive relationships with customers.
- Opening Demat accounts of the customers.
- Recommending new IPO's to the existing customers.

Employment History

MARG SKILLS PRIVATE LIMITED

(A Unit of MARG Group & SEI CMMI Level 3 Co.)

New Delhi, Delhi April 2021 - Present

Executive - HR (Generalist)

Key Responsibilities Handled:

RECRUITMENT:-

- Sourcing candidates on Naukari.com from PAN India location as per the requirement getting from the Project Managers & other departments.
- Screening the candidates through a detailed phone call discussion, evaluating candidate's compatibility with the specific job requirement, ensuring a right fit prior to shortlisting.
- Align the next round of interviews with the concerned person on Microsoft Teams, Google Meet, or Face to Face.
- If the candidate has been selected for the required profile, the next step is to negotiate on salary & close the profile within the company's budget & time frame.
- Issuing the offer letter & making sure to get them on board on the given date.

INDUCTION & ON-BOARDING:-

- Collection of documentation of all new hires by a teammate and continued to build files with the HR protocol.
- Cross-check the employee's files by checking application forms, statutory forms & all employee-related documents to finalization of record with no error.
- Post documentation, makes new hires understand the company's policies like leave policies, office timing policies, business attire, & the company's culture, and an office tour in an Induction Program.
- Informed the departments' HOD via email about the SPOC for the necessary arrangements for the new hire to perform the tasks, such as sitting arrangements, assets & system configuration.
- Sending welcome emails to new hires & other details to the concerned department to create their official email id & identity card.
- Assist with the new hire in month-end regarding opening their new bank accounts by our bank agent.
- Conducted training for all employees, supervisors, and managers on processes related to the ESS panel.

OPERATIONS:-

- Preparing Offers Letters, Annexure, and Appointment Letters for a large number of resources every month.
- Issued letters in bulk (up to 90 in a month) by mass mailing.
- Updating Master sheet with all the new joinings, transfers & exits.
- Engaged with the exit formalities of the employees including sharing clearance forms to employees & taking exit interviews, to sum up with a feedback form.
- Preparing full and final settlements & making sure to settle the accounts of the left

- employee within the given time frame.
- Preparing Experience & Reliving Letters & issuing them to ex-staff after their settlement.
- Doing settlements towards PF, Gratuity, and PL Encashment of ex-staff as per company policy.
- Issuing Announcements, Advisory, Warnings, Invitations to everyone via mail.

PAYROLL MANAGEMENT:-

Processing the payroll for approximately **300** employees of 3 companies of Marg Group, uploading the input of same in the system, and validating the same. – **(using HRMS developed by MARG)**

- Collect the monthly attendance from all Centres/locations in an excel sheet by EOM.
- Compiled attendances into three different consolidated attendance sheets.
- Make the changes in the consolidated sheets according to the leave adjustments.
- After finalization, get the sheet approved by the hierarchical authority.
- Post-approval, mark the attendance into payroll software manually and sync the attendance of the HO employees into the software.
- During the preparation of salary, need to add data of new joinings & remove exit employees of the month.
- Register the salary post attendance & generate the salary sheets department-wise and cross-check all the data.
- Get the approval on the salary sheet from the company's director.
- Share all the salary sheets to the Accounts & Finance team to further process & ensure that the salary has been credited into the beneficiary account on the due date.
- Resolve the payroll query of employees by mail, telephonic, and face-to-face discussion.
- Handling software like HRXpert (Payroll Software) and ESS Panel (Leave Mgmt.& PMS Management)
- After payroll processing, prepare the MIS Reports for our record.
 - Successfully created, reviewed & distributed various payroll reports to support financial projections, audits, HR reviews, and compliance issues.

GRIEVANCE HANDLING:-

- Handled queries related to PF withdrawal requests, data updates & KYC pending requests on the EPFO portal.
- Handled gueries regarding requests for ESI cards to claim the services of ESIC.
- Received queries from centers for their leave adjustment on different occasions.
- Received queries from left employees regarding their F&F clearance & relieving letters.
- Up-to-date employees about the policies on their requirements for clarification.
- Responded to employee issues and questions promptly.
- Handeled queries based on the ESS panel related to attendance, out duty, leave approvals, and other approvals.

EMPLOYEE ENGAGEMENT & RELATIONS:-

- Coined the concept of Employee Engagement Activities, broadly classified and differentiated it into the following heads: Reward & Recognition, Fun Hour Activity, Zumba (Fitness) Activity, Team Building Activities, and Yoga Session & Activities to build the culture of the organization.
- Employee retention by ensuring a friendly and conducive environment. Providing a patient hearing to employees and making sure that relevant ideas and suggestions from all levels are implemented without much delay.
- Organized Birthday Celebrations, Wedding Anniversary Celebrations, Employees get-together, and major Festival Celebrations in our office terrace area.
- Activities which have been organized once a year such as a Bike/Scooty race for both male & female employees and a Cricket Championship named MPL (Marg Premier League).

STATUTORY COMPLIANCES:-

- Frequently visits on government platforms for the latest notification for minimum wages into PAN India.
- Registration of New Members in EPFO and update their KYC.
- Registration of New Members at ESIC Portal, Updating their family details, Dispensary location, Aadhaar Card & Bank Details.
- The practice of PF withdrawal, Joint declaration/Corrections, online claims & funds transfer.
- Handling salary, wages administration & labor welfare fund.
- Gratuity calculation based on the completion of the required period of the employee.
- Leave Management includes managing casual leave, earned leave, and encashing the earned leaves by entering into the new financial year.

CALANCE SOFTWARE PRIVATE LIMITED

(A SEI CMMI Level 5 Company)

Gurugram, Haryana January 2020 –March 2021

Executive -HR & Admin

Key Responsibilities Handled:

- Coordination with recruitment team of Calance regarding new hire.
- Assisted in creating documentation for all new hires, and continued to build files following HR protocol.
- Make sure the Induction/onboarding experience of the new employees should be remarkable.
- Maintaining the employee master sheet updating New Joining's, Transfers, and Exits
- Connect with the bank executive for opening Salary Bank Accounts of the new hire.
- Assisting in creating the F&F statement of the leaving employee and making sure all the exit formality has been done.

- Developed and implemented company policies and codes that supported longterm and short-term goals
- Assisted in updating all benefits information, while extending important knowledge pertaining to benefits to employees.
- Leaves management: ensure the prompt and accurate processing of leaves and generate documentation, data management, file management.
- Processed confirmation of probation of the employees.
- Handling grievances of the employees related to Salary, PF, ESIC, and Income Tax.
- Issuing letters ex. Offer Generation, Appointment Letter, Warning Letter, and Increment Letter as per the company's protocol.
- Vendor Management: Making sure of payments as per the final invoice and coordination for printing new ID Cards for the new hire.
- Processing monthly Reimbursement with prior approvals.
- Handling documentation of the employee's investment declarations for TDS calculations & preparing the report on excel workbook.
- Coordinate with the consultant regarding PF, ESIC, LWF, and Gratuity.
- Make sure all the files & documents at the reception are up to date.
- Handling CATS for attendance of the employees.

MF BUMI GEOTECH PRIVATE LIMITED

(A Company of BUMI Group)

New Delhi, Delhi August 2018 - January 2020

Executive - Human Resource

Key Responsibilities Handled:

- Worked as a reliable and dedicated team member in the HR department, dedicated to fostering the mission of Bumi Group.
- Handling end-to-end recruitment (Sourcing to On-boarding).
- Coordinating with HOD's for a better understanding of the requirements of recruitment & preparing Job Descriptions for the same.
- Drafting and issuing letters Vij. Offer Letter, Appointment Letter, Transfer letter, and Increment Letter.
- Taking care of joining formalities, induction & Onboarding of new employees.
- Preparing files for new Joining & updating the earlier ones with exits & transfers.
- Reported important days and Festivals to Management for future events.
- Handled documentation work regarding EPF & ESI.
- Developing & administering health & safety programs with the concern of the Fire & Safety Manager.
- Maintaining attendance records of all the employees of the organization.
- Maintaining employee master data including new Joining, Transfers, and Exits.
- Visited different sites of the company for HR audit purposes.

PAMHO HR SOLUTIONS

New Delhi, Delhi August 2016 - July 2017

HR Recruiter

Key Responsibilities Handled:

- Worked as an IT Talent sourcer, responsible to manage the whole life cycle of the recruitment for clients.
- Research, identify and qualify candidates for IT positions.
- Worked on various Job portals such as Naukri.com, Shine.com, and LinkedIn
 including employee referrals to source the best talent who can be shown as a good
 fit for the open positions provided by the clients.
- Publish & manage job ads on Naukri.com.
- Screening the candidates through a detailed phone call discussion, evaluating candidate's compatibility with the specific job requirement, ensuring a right fit prior to submission to the client.
- Sharing the company profile, job description, company-related articles, and interview details with the candidates through MS Outlook.
- Edit and reformat resumes with the help of MS Word as the client's requirements.
- Scheduling the telephonic/onsite interviews for shortlisted candidates, coordinating between candidates and the hiring manager till the offer is made.
- Negotiating with the candidates on pay rate expectations.
- Maintaining the candidate's database in MS Excel for other possible opportunities in the future.
- Continuous follow-up with candidates for onboarding.

Professional Skills

Microsoft Office : Intermediate (Outlook, Excel, Word, and

PowerPoint).

Communication : Excellent Communication Skills.

HR Policy and Regulation : Excellent.

Event Planning : Excellent

Employment Laws : Good

Tally ERP 9.0 : Good

Other Qualifications

Prayag Sangeet Samiti Prayagraj, Allahabad, Senior Diploma in Vocal (Classic Music) Graduated June 2019

Prayag Sangeet Samiti Prayagraj, Allahabad,
Junior Diploma in Vocal (Classic Music) Graduated June 2015

Interest & Hobbies

- Listening Music
- Traveling to the different States of India
- Reading Books

Languages

Hindi : Native

English: Professional and Conversational

Personal Details

Father's Name : Mr. Ram Prakash Sharma

Date of Birth : 22 March 1996
Marital Status : Unmarried

Blood Group: O -ve

Permanent Address : RZ-20, Bajaj Enclave, Old Palam Road,

Dwarka Sec-15, New Delhi - 110078

Date:

Place: Karan Sharma